

Junior Kaningini L.

Machine Learning Engineer and Computer Security Expert

- Lukala 50/Ngaliema/Kinshasa
- ► Email: nkaningini@aimsammi.org
- Tel: +243817138062 +243817138062 (WhatsApp)
- GitHub
- LinkedIn
- Web page

Skills

HTML+CSS+PHP+JS	6+ Years
Python,Java,C#,VB	7+ Years
Cyber security	4+ Years.
Network Management	4+ Years.
System Linux, Windows	6+ Years.
Web development	6+ Years.
Machine Learning	5+ Year.
Blockchain	4+ Years.
Internet of things	4+ Years.
Cloud computing	5+ Years.
Latex	4+ Years.

Langues

Français	++++
Anglais	+++
Swahili	++++
Lingala	++++

Summary

I am a passionate researcher in machine learning and computer security. I have a strong background in data science, machine learning and computer security. In addition to computer security and machine learning, I am also a web developer and have a strong background in network and operating system administration on Linux and Windows. I have knowledge in human resources management, project management and administration, public management. I am able to adapt to a new environment and have analytical and problem solving skills.

Experience

Assistant of IT Manager | AIMS-Senegal

Feb 2021 - August 2021

African Institute for Mathematical Sciences

As an assistant to the IT Manager, I had to design and implement a management application for the AIMS-SENEGAL Center including several functionalities such as data analysis, information system security, financial management, academic management, etc..

Trainee at AIMS-SENEGAL

October 2020-Feb 2021

African Institute for Mathematical Sciences

The internship was in the IT department where I was the assistant of the IT Manager. During the internship, I had to develop a management application for the AIMS SENGAL center. Network and operating system administration were also part of my tasks..

Founder of the company JKnTech

March 2019 - Now

Kinshasa / Democratic Repuplic of Congo

JKTech is a multi-sectoral technology company because it works in several fields including Data Analysis (Big Data and Machine Learning), Development (web, mobile, desktop), Information Systems Security (IT security), Internet of Things (IoT), Blockchain Technology, Network Administration and System Administration (Linux, Windows, etc....), Computer Design (Photo and Video Editing), Entrepreneurship, and the company has a training center for capacity building in the various areas mentioned above

National president of PPJ | DRC

September 2015 - Now

Youth Popular Podium

PPJ is a platform for young people with several objectives in different fields including education, the environment, agriculture, new information technology, etc. I coordinate all activities done by the organization.

Assistant at UNIKIN | DRC

Juin 2017 - Now

University of Kinshasa in DRC

My tasks included: Computer Security, Operating System, Computer Network, Computer Architecture, Architecture of Teleinformatic Systems, Operating System Design, etc...

Trainer at IT Department of

Sept 2016- March 2017

The Ministry of Finance / KINSHASA (DRC)

With the task of managing the payroll application

Education

31 Jan 2022 - 5 Dec 2022

Master in Artificial Intelligence (AMMI)

African Institute of Mathematical Sciences (AIMS-Senegal)

Machine Learning

Sept 2019 - Feb 2021

Master in Mathematical Science

African Institute of Mathematical Sciences (AIMS-Senegal)

Option: Computer Security

September 2014 - Sept 2016

Bachelor's degree in Mathematic and Computer Science

University of Kinshasa / DRC

Option: Computer Engineering

September 2011 - Sept 2014

Graduate diploma in Science

University of Kinshasa / DRC

July 2010

State diploma in Mathematic and Physics

Kalumbwa Institute / DRC / South Kivu / Shabunda

Interests

- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Operational Research
- ▶ IBM Cloud, Coursera
- Travel
- Music
- ▶ Sport : Soccer, running

Certificates

OCTOBER 2022: Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification

MAY 2022 : Certified in Cybersecurity Intro
MAY 2022 : Certified in Machine Learning V2

JULY 2021: Python for Data Science, Al and Development

 $\begin{array}{lll} \mbox{August 2020}: & \mbox{Certified on Responsive Web Design} \\ \mbox{August 2020}: & \mbox{Certified on Blockchain Basics} \\ \mbox{August 2020}: & \mbox{Certified on Cryptography} \end{array}$

AUGUST 2020: Certified on HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers

AUGUST 2020 : Certified on Hardware Security

JULY 2020 : Hardware Security on the Building a Google Firebase Web Application
JULY 2020 : Introduction to the Internet of Things and Embedded Systems

JULY 2020 : Certified on the Usable Security

JUN 2020 : Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure
MAY 2020 : Certified on the Blockchain and Cryptocurrency Explained
MAY 2020 : Certified on the Industrial IoT on Google Cloud Platform
APRIL 2020 : Certified on Blockchain: Foundations and Use Cases
APRIL 2020 : Certified on Build the Voting Application using Blockchain

APRIL 2020 : Certified on Cyber Threats and Attack Vectors

APRIL 2020 : Certified on Python /IBM

APRIL 2020 : Certified on Enterprise System Management and Security

MARCH 2020 : Certified on Identify and Investigate Cybersecurity Threats /IBM

FEBRUARY 2020 : | Certified on Internet of Things (IoT) /IBM

January 2020 : Certified on Blockchain Intro /IBM
May 2018 : Certified on Linux System Administration

Ref: Campus Numérique Fraconcophone(DRC/KINSHASA)

FEBRUARY2018 : Certified on Linux Network administration

Ref: Campus Numérique Fraconcophone(DRC/KINSHASA)

MARCH 2016 : Interface-Homme-Machine (IHM)

Conferences

AUGUST 2022: Cryptography and Number Theory/CIMPA Senegal

Jun 2022 : A mathematical modelling perspective on ecology, biodiversity August 2021 : Summer School on Quantum Thermodynamics/Zurich University

 $May\ 2018$: Algorithmic arithmetic and cryptography/CIMPA-DRC

References

Professor Mouhamed Moustapha Fall

Position: President of AIMS Senegal

EMAIL: mouhamed.m.fall@aims-senegal.org

Professor Pierre Kafunda Katalay

POSITION: University of KINSHASA EMAIL: kafundakatalay@gmail.com

Mouhamed Lamine Diallo

POSITION: IT Manager of AIMS-Senegal EMAIL: mldiallo@aims-senegal.org